{"tossups": [{"question": "This building\u2019s gate includes the inscription \u201cO Soul, thou art at rest\u201d from the 89th sura of the Quran. It lies on the south bank of the Yamuna River, north of a garden with a pool reflecting this building\u2019s image. Its design includes four minarets, four small domes, and a large primary dome, and it was built as a tomb for Mumtaz, the emperor\u2019s wife. Shah Jahan built, for ten points, what Muslim mausoleum in Agra, a masterpiece of Indian architecture?", "answer": "<b> Taj Mahal</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "An attempt to implicate Jews for one of this man\u2019s actions involved an apron located just below the Goulston Street graffito; that apron belonged to Catherine Eddows. That event proved that this man\u2019s\u201cDear Boss\u201d letter wasn\u2019t a hoax. Later, this man mailed a kidney to George Lusk with his \u201cFrom Hell\u201dLetter. For ten points, name this officially unidentified serial killer of London\u2019s Whitechapel district.", "answer": "<b> Jack the Ripper</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "After Martin Luther called Henry VIII a pig, dolt, and liar, this author returned fire in<em> Responsio ad</em> <em>Lutherum</em>. A decade later, he was executed for treason after refusing to support Henry VIII\u2019s annulment. Peter Giles and Raphael Hythloday discuss an imaginary island in one of this man\u2019s works. For ten points, name this English Christian Humanist who wrote<em> Utopia</em>.", "answer": "Thomas<b> More</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A photo by Yevgeny Khaldei [khal-DAY] shows a soldier raising a flag atop a building in this city. In this city, the mural<em> My God, Help Me to Survive This Deadly Love</em> depicts Leonid Brezhnev and Erich Honecker embracing. Lucius D. Clay led relief during Operation Vittles which was known as this city\u2019s\u201cAirlift\u201d. For ten points, name this capital of Germany.", "answer": "<b> Berlin</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This 1972 presidential candidate of the American Independent Party was paralyzed by Arthur Bremer on the campaign trail; that attack was not in response to this politician\u2019s controversial positions, including his 1963 vow of \u201csegregation now, segregation tomorrow, segregation forever\u201d. For ten points, name this governor whose \u201cStand in the Schoolhouse Door\u201d failed to prevent the integration of the University of Alabama.", "answer": "George<b> Wallace</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Nigel DeGray and William Montgomery in Room 40 led efforts to translate this document. An agent for one country named \u201cMr. H\u201d bribed a Western Union employee to send this document to another destination. This document was sent to Venustiano Carranza by diplomat Heinrich von Eckardt, who suggested that Texas might be regained from the United States if the Central Powers were victorious. For ten points, name this controversial German diplomatic message that asked Mexico to join World War I.", "answer": "<b> Zimmerman telegram</b> (accept synonyms for telegram)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this race inspired by a Greek battle, with a length of about 26 miles.", "answer": "<b> marathon</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "During one election, this man touted his war service with the slogan \u201cCongress needs a tail gunner,\u201dhelping him defeat Robert M. LaFollette, Jr.. The Tydings Committee investigated a claim made by this man during a speech in Wheeling, West Virginia. Joseph Welch asked this man \u201cAt long last, have you no sense of decency?\u201d during military hearings in 1954. For ten points, name this senator who fueled the Red Scare with his hunts for Communists in the federal government.", "answer": "Joseph Raymond<b> McCarthy</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man was deported after he was accused of mail fraud during his purchase of the<em> SS Yarmouth</em>. This man, who was called the \u201cmost dangerous enemy of the Negro race\u201d by W.E.B. Du Bois, is worshiped as a prophet of God by Rastafarians. He founded the Black Star Line to promote his mission as the founder of the Universal Negro Improvement Association. For ten points, name this Jamaican native who promoted the Back-to-Africa movement.", "answer": "Marcus Mosiah<b> Garvey</b>, Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This party lost an election to Stanley Baldwin due to the Zinoviev Letter. This party\u2019s 1983 election manifesto was called by one man as the \u201clongest suicide note in history\u201d. James Callaghan of this party suffered the Winter of Discontent which saw the rise of the opposition party\u2019s leader Margaret Thatcher. For ten points, name this British political party formerly led by Ed Milliband which opposes the Conservatives and Liberals.", "answer": "United Kingdom<b> Labour</b> Party", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This organization wiped out the Western Federation of Miners\u2019 treasury by infiltrating its staff and providing too much food to strikers. The founder of this organization gained notoriety after foiling an apparent plot to assassinate Abraham Lincoln through Baltimore. One employee of this organization, James McParland, spied on the Molly Maguires, and Henry Clay Frick hired this group as security for scabs during the Homestead Strike. For ten points, name this American detective agency, known as \u201cthe Pinks.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Pinkerton</b> (National) Detective Agency (accept the<b> Pinkerton</b>s)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": " Smith and Carlos took first and third in the 200 meter event in this sport. Justin Gatlinâ€™s 2006 record in the 100 meter event, at 9.766 seconds, was rescinded after a doping scandal.", "answer": "<b> track</b> and field (accept<b> sprint</b>ing,<b> run</b>ning, or other short-distance examples; do not accept hurdles)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Senate Bill 3225 was an attempt to disclose the full text of this treaty. A humorous website dedicated to this treaty directs the reader to stopfasttrack.com. One politician</b> <b>claimed that this treaty \u201cis much more than a (+)</b> <b>claimed that this treaty \u201cis much more than a (+)</b> <b>free trade agreement,\u201d and this</b> <b>agreement is the successor to the TPSEP. (*)</b> Vietnam, Australia, Canada, and the United Vietnam, Australia, Canada, and the United States are in talks regarding, for ten points, what proposed trade agreement between twelve Pacific Rim countries?", "answer": "<b> T</b>rans-<b>P</b>acific-<b>P</b>artnership", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After three rounds of intense questioning regarding her role in this event, the innocent Violet Sharp committed suicide. The perpetrator of this event left a note signed with</b> <b>two interconnected blue circles around a red circle; that (+)</b> <b>ransom note demanded fifty</b> <b>ransom note demanded fifty</b> <b>thousand dollars and claimed that the subject of this event was (*)</b> <b>thousand dollars and claimed that the subject of this event was (*)</b> \u201cin good care.\u201d Bruno Hauptmann was executed for committing, for ten points, what 1932 \u201cCrime of the Century\u201d in which the toddler son of a famous aviator was abducted and killed?", "answer": "the<b> kidnapping</b> (and/or)<b> murder</b> of Charles<b> Lindbergh, Jr.</b> (or of the<b> Lindbergh baby </b>or similar descriptions; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Project Seal attempted to use bombs to generate these events. They have low amplitude</b> <b>but long (+)</b> <b>wavelength, which make them difficult to detect until they undergo shoaling</b> <b>in shallow areas. (*)</b> Warnings about the oncoming of these events are issued from a center in Hawai\u2019i. For ten points, floods in Japanese coastal cities are often due to what kind of very large wave that is typically caused by an earthquake?", "answer": "<b> tsunami</b> (prompt \u201ctidal waves\u201d)", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Earth Science"}, {"question": "<b>The fall of this government led to the deportation of many to New Caledonia. Gustave</b> <b>Courbet was a member of this government, which ordered the fall of the (+)</b> <b>Vendome</b> <b>Column. Many of this government\u2019s officials were executed on the Wall of the Federalists in P`ere Lachaise Cemetery. (*)</b> Marshall MacMahon led an army that repressed this government during the \u201cBloody Week\u201d. For ten points, name this radical socialist government that formed in the French capital in 1871.", "answer": "<b> Paris Commune</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>The case</b><em><b> DeFunis v. Odegaard</b></em><b> would have considered the constitutionality of this policy, but was rendered moot. A quota system could (+) not implement this policy, according to the Supreme Court\u2019s ruling in the</b><em><b> Bakke</b></em><b> case.</b><em><b> Gratz v. Bollinger</b></em><b> ruled that (*)</b> Michigan\u2019s 150-point scale, which provided 20 points to beneficiaries of this policy but only 12 points for a perfect SAT score, was unconstitutional. For ten points, name this policy of favoring minority groups for employment or school admissions.", "answer": "<b> affirmative action</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker!", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Scott McKenzie called for people to come to this city with \u201cflowers in your hair\u201d</b> <b>a few months before it hosted the Monterey Pop Festival. In this city, a community</b> <b>at (+)</b> <b>Haight Ashbury signalled its end with a mock funeral called \u201cThe Death of</b> <b>the Hippie.\u201d Dan White murdered this city\u2019s first openly gay public official, Harvey</b> <b>(*)</b> Milk. The \u201cSummer of Love\u201d took place in, for ten points, what California city across a bay from Oakland?", "answer": "<b> San Francisco</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}